It was my fault.
I drove her to this.
That seems to be the case.
The hope you showed her caused her to fall into despair.
Because of that, her time as a magical girl came to its proper end.
You sound happy.
Well, what happened isn't tragic.
Your hope and the despair that eventually follows
is what allow us to extend the lifespan of the universe.
Thanks to your sac-
That's all we're good for?
Aren't magical girls supposed to save people?
What's the point of having powers if we can't save anyone with them?
Why couldn't I save Kuroi and Ui?
Why?
You know why you couldn't.
You pretended to understand them, but you didn't know a thing.
Even if you did, you can't actually do anything to help.
You just lie to yourself and think you know.
No, you're lying.
How many magical girls do you think are going to become witches now?
Huh?
How many magical girls do you think will become witches
now that you stopped the Magius' plan?
You're saying...
I'm responsible?
It's my fault?
See?
You don't know a thing.
Iroha!
Can you hear me?
I'm sorry, Yachiyo.
But I shouldn't have ever become a magical girl.
You're spacing out, Iroha!
Snap out of it!
We'll be up in a sec, so hang in there!
We're not giving up on you!
Talk to us, Iroha!
Say something!
I know you're in pain and feeling like you failed,
but don't keep it to yourself!
Share it with us!
Hey, you guys!
Now that we're all together,
let's combine our hope and despair!
The hatred we're never ever gonna forget!
The loneliness from being alone!
Our fear and anxiety!
Past selves we can't forgive!
Our failures that we can't undo!
All that and our hope, too!
Thank you for coming to my rescue!
You don't have to thank us, Iroha!
It's because of you that we made it this far!
Hey, um, where are Toka and Nemu?
They're using Embryo Eve to go after Valpurgisnacht.
If we don't stop them,
the shockwave after they fuse with it will destroy the city!
I warned you!
Now that you know,
you'll have to choose who you're going to save!
Yeah, I know that!
Well, are we ready to fail again?
No matter how many times I fail,
the piece of me who lives in my friends from Mikazuki Villa
will help me remember hope!
You're part of me, too.
And even if you give up,
that piece of me inside everyone else
will always reach out to me!
I didn't know anything about you, Kuroi.
Please forgive me.
Hey, everyone!
Lend me your power!
I'm gonna need it to stop Toka and Nemu!
I can't let them sacrifice themselves!
Those two are like my little sisters!
We're in time.
There she is.
While Pergus knocked.
Just as we calculated.
Yep.
It won't be long till she's right on top of Mitakihara.
Let's keep those two busy
until the other magical girls can catch up with us!
If we're crying out loud, it's her again!
Did you see that, Kaide?
We'll be just fine on our own now.
Would Momoko be proud of us if she were here?
Yeah, of course she'd be!
I bet you'd say we're strong enough now to do anything!
Those chains won't hold Embryo E for long!
Get ready to focus your attacks!
Dealing with kids is such a drag!
Could all of you please think rationally?
The big magical girls we're stuck with isn't there,
and our plan is the quickest and best way to free us from it!
But it's not right!
Toka and Nemu, you have to stop this right now!
W-what are you doing here?
We sealed you away.
I saw Ui, and she let me out!
Even she knows that doing things this way won't save anyone!
You have nothing to worry about.
If there are any casualties, it won't be anybody you know.
And if anyone should die,
we're the ones who'd be responsible for killing them, not you.
You have nothing to do with it.
How can you say stuff like that?
I feel responsible for you!
You're like my sisters!
And you know me and Ui well enough to know we'd never be okay with this!
I know you always make other people the priority instead of yourself,
but you should care about yourself more.
I can say the same about you guys.
You cared about Ui and me, and look what happened.
This is my fault.
All of this.
If it wasn't for me,
you wouldn't have become magical girls in the first place.
What a stupid thing to say!
You big dummy!
Who cares whose fault it was?
You staying alive and having more time to spend with us is all we wanted!
Having more time to spend together
would have made us all a lot happier, wouldn't it?
Well, it's a lot better than having less time.
You know, you're right.
It is a lot better.
So why don't you stay with me now?
Stay with me every second you can.
None of this other stuff,
saving magical girls or whatever,
none of it would matter if I didn't have you.
I couldn't bear it
if you just disappeared out of my life again.
Don't leave me alone like that.
Come on, stay with me.
Don't go leaving your big sis alone.
Please don't cry.
Yes, top it.
I will.
As long as you let me love you
with whatever time I have left.
That's so not fair!
How could you say that?
It's like you think I don't want to be around you or something,
which is totally wrong!
You think I don't love you?
Is that it?
How could you think that?
You're like the biggest, dumbest dummy in the world!
We worked so hard to forget those happy times.
And here you are,
making us remember again.
It's okay.
Don't ever leave us, ever.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
There, there, it's okay.
Nothing's gonna come between us ever again.
I promise.
Incoming!
Ciao, ciao!
How are all you goody-goody girls doing today?
It's Alina Kray.
Now don't you worry, Toka and Nemo.
The poor Rivoluzione you and your little feathers tried to make isn't done.
It just needs Alina's touch to completare it.
Yeah, about that, the plan's sort of changed now.
I have grande respeto for you both,
and your arte emotiva inspired me to create something.
I'll turn all humanity into magical girls.
Whatever game you think you're playing, you better stop.
First, I'll fuse my Doppel with Embryo E.
Then steal all Pergusnot's power.
And then, I'll force my new Doppel onto every human on the planet.
They'll all have magic powers like us,
but without any grief seeds.
Their Doppels will take them over one by one
until they've all been turned into witches.
Do you get it?
They'll share the same fate as us.
It's brillante!
That's stupid!
The whole point of our plan was to liberate magical girls,
but you want to go and make more?
You do realize this plan of yours won't be saving anyone, right?
My latest work will show the world
that magical girls are real and really angry.
Liberating magical girls is fine,
but my show will be itchitante!
We were trying to save us, not put on a show!
In a few moments,
the story that is Alina Gray
will scop the air into a flame of creativity!
Alina will make everything into arte so gorgeous,
you'll all thank me for it!
Ciao, goody-goodies!
Ciao, Mophis!
Ciao, Alina Gray!
Stop her!
Don't let her go!
Alina's going after Valpurgisnacht!
Nemo,
we have to finish the plan.
Yes, Toka, let's complete it.
We just have one last sacrifice to make
and this will be over.
Ah!
No matter how many unforgivable things we've done,
becoming magical girls to protect our big sis
is the one thing we won't ever regret.
It was the right thing to do.
Big sis, go live a wrong life and be happy.
Live well for us and for Ui.
Toka, Nemo, don't do that!
Thanks for coming to help, Ui!
Together to the end, as we plan.
What is this?
Did I die?
Mel and Kanai, I guess I did die.
No, we're not ghosts.
What is this?
Did I die?
Mel and Kanai, I guess I did die.
No, we're not ghosts.
I'm the magic I used to have before I died.
I've been a part of you since then.
I had no idea that when any of my friends died,
I had the power to collect their magic like some kind of prize.
What a disgusting ability.
I'm so sorry.
You don't have to be sorry about a thing.
It's not about collecting magic like you're gobbling up more power for yourself or something.
It's the power to keep our hopes alive in you.
You're not ghosts.
I'm the magic I used to have before I died.
I've been a part of you since then.
I had no idea that when any of my friends died,
I had the power to collect their magic like some kind of prize.
What a disgusting ability.
I'm so sorry.
You don't have to be sorry about a thing.
It's not about collecting magic like you're gobbling up more power for yourself or something.
It's the power to keep our hopes alive in you.
I'm keeping your hopes alive in me?
That's right.
And as long as you live, our hopes will continue to live on too.
Yep.
That'll be rough sometimes, lugging our hopes around with you,
but we appreciate it.
You're more than capable of carrying your own hope.
Mifuyu, when you finally leave the wings of the Magius,
would you like to move back to Mikazuki Villa?
Are you serious?
Yes, I am.
I'd love to.
I'll take the living room then.
I think I'll be happy there.
Plus, I can keep my eye on everyone.
I'll take the living room too.
The house has plenty of empty rooms that are more charming.
Besides, Momoko, you already live close by.
Why?
I want to have the living room too.
Honestly, what's gotten into everyone?
Looks like we're at the last stop.
Alright.
See you later.
Wait, can't we hang out a little longer?
Sorry.
We have to get going.
Goodbye, Ya-chan.
Take care.
Momoko.
Mifuyu.
How long how long?
Mifuyu?
Mifuyu.
I wish I could, but you want to know something?
What?
My body is made of magic.
Or actually, a whole lot of usses.
Smaller than the tiniest atom and too many to count.
These little usses fill in the outlines between rage, sorrow, or hope.
Sometimes as doppels, sometimes as magical girls.
They're always there.
Why are you telling me all this?
If you think about when you were with me, do you remember if you were happy?
Yeah, of course I was happy!
What kind of question is that?
Whenever we were together, I was always happy!
Well, anytime you're feeling happy, I'll be a part of that now.
All you have to do is look for me and you'll find me.
I'll be in all the happiness you feel.
Huh?
Don't you see?
You don't have to cry for me anymore.
Louie!
When you're happy, just look for me in your heart.
Because it's when you're happy that I'll be able to see you again.
And we can be together again.
Okay.
I will.
Yachiyuuu!
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
She's still alive!
You should have listened.
Now that you know, are you better off?
If you stayed oblivious, you wouldn't be suffering now.
No, that's not true.
Before, I was scared of you.
I didn't want to understand you.
But now that I know everything I know, I can take your hand.
I can worry with you.
And suffer with you.
Now I know what you are.
You're part of me.
I won't look away anymore now.
No matter what part of me I see.
Now I can say, I'm glad I became a magical girl.
What?
It's Iroha Tamaki.
This is...
Ui's power of collection.
What?
This is the power to carry my friend's hope.
You're a part of all this too, Kuroi.
Yachiyo...
Shall we go?
Yeah, let's.
Ui, Toka, Nemu, Kuroi...
No matter how much I regret, or how sad I am, I won't give up. I'll keep going.
I know I'm not alone anymore.
And if I stumble, I know you'll be there to reach out to.
Now, let me hear your voices again!
I cannot have good horn from providing this way I have to trust.
Today is so much easier.
I'm going to eat a boss in the world and hope to come out later.
Just remember.
Please, if you will check your heart out, H vocal.
Therat,iği, Or Aang, have not heard of.
Thank you.
No one will ever know all the wishes we made.
No one will ever know all the struggles we had.
No one will ever know how hard we cried sometimes.
No one will ever know the anger and rage we felt.
No one will ever know how we failed to do what we set out to.
No one will ever know about the beliefs in the arts Alina made.
No one will ever know that we were lied to and stolen from.
Or that we fought back.
No one will ever know how we dreamed of hope.
How we tried to secure it.
And how we failed.
No one will ever know the sacrifices we made to save the lives of the ones we loved.
People think this damage was caused by an earthquake, a typhoon, and a terrorist attack.
Which coincidentally happened all at once here.
Thanks to you, the truth will never be known.
The existence of Magical Girls and what really happened here will never be written down or spoken of.
Great work, Iroha Tamaki.
No one will ever know.
But I'll never forget what happened.
This is our record.
For us to know.
And no one else.